

Research Interest

My research interests primarily encompass Information Retrieval (IR) and Question Answering (QA). I aim to explore how language, whether in conversations, audio, or text, can be represented as question + external information = answer. My specific areas of focus include Open-Domain Question Answering, Fact Verification, and addressing the challenge of Hallucination or Confabulation in responses.

Education

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology

Seoul, S.Korea

M.S. IN ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE

Mar. 2023 - Present

Advisor: James Thorne Co-Advisor: Jinwoo Shin

Berkeley, CA USA

University of California, Berkeley B.A. IN STATISTICS

Aug. 2012 - Aug. 2017

Publications

CLICK: A Benchmark Dataset of Cultural and Linguistic Intelligence in Korean

LREC-COLING 2024

EUNSU KIM, JUYOUNG SUK, PHILHOON OH, HANEUL YOO, JAMES THORNE AND ALICE OH

Feb. 2024

In the 2024 Joint International Conference on Computational Linguistics, Language Resources and Evaluation, 2024

Detrimental Contexts in Open-Domain Question Answering

EMNLP Findings

PHILHOON OH, AND JAMES THORNE

Sep. 2023

• In The 2023 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing, 2023

Knowledge Corpus Error in Question Answering

EMNLP Findings

YEJOON LEE, PHILHOON OH, AND JAMES THORNE

Sep. 2023

• In The 2023 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing, 2023

Work Experience_

NAVER Corp Gyeonggi-do, S.Korea

Jan. 2024 - Feb. 2024 RESEARCH INTERN

- Designed a pipeline to generate datasets to train Korean evaluation models.
- Refined the evaluation model, achieving a Pearson Correlation of 0.846, compared to the baseline of 0.698

SK Inc. C&C Gyeonggi-do, S.Korea

NLP ENGINEER & PL

Jan. 2019 - Feb. 2022

- Developed NLP framework based on Pytorch for various NLP models and subsequent tasks.
- Designed pipelines for NLP tasks including MRC, ODQA, Keyword Extraction.
- Implemented automated pipeline for Korean Text Crawling and Pre-processing.
- Led NLP Keyword Extraction project.

Anemone Boutique LLC

Santa Monica, CA USA

Oct. 2017 - Mar. 2018

- Analyzed the impacts of different marketing strategies.
- Implemented time series analysis (SARIMA) on previous quarters data to predict future sales.

Projects

MARKETING ANALYST

ChatGPT Project

GRADUATE STUDENT ADVISOR

Seoul, S.Korea

Feb. 2023 - Dec. 2023

· Conducted research on how ChatGPT works with non-English languages advised by James Thorne and Alice Oh.

- Mentored undergraduate students at KAIST on ChatGPT and fundamental NLP research topics.
- Led and guided undergraduate students in a research project; paper accepted at LREC-COLING 2024.

Korean ODQA Project Gyeonggi-do, S.Korea

NLP ENGINEER Jul. 2021 - Dec. 2021

- Developed a Korean ODQA (Open Domain Question Answering) feature.
- · Achieved performance improvements on datasets, including Korquad v1, Al common sense, and the XX hospital dataset.

Chatbot PoC Gyeonggi-do, S.Korea

NLP ENGINEER

Jul. 2021 - Sep. 2021

- · Demonstrated the Open-Domain Question Answering (ODQA) feature to one of the largest hospitals in Korea, the client
- The ODQA feature was integrated as an NLP feature through a PoC.

Survey Project Gyeonggi-do, S.Korea

NLP ENGINEER & PL

Jul. 2021 - Aug. 2021

- Developed a survey feedback tool for the SK SUPEX Council (Consultative Panel within SK Group).
- Implemented the Keyword Extractor module to collect feedback from anonymous ethical surveys.

NLP Framework Gyeonggi-do, S.Korea

NLP ENGINEER

Jan. 2021 - Jun. 2021

- Participated in developing an integrated NLP framework based on PyTorch.
- Designed a new architecture to support various NLP models based on tasks and features.
- Developed unit tests for the framework using the pytest module.

Honors & Awards

2023 **2nd Place**, 2023 AI Graduate School Challenge

Seoul, S.Korea

2017 Manga Cum Laude, High Distinction in General Scholarship at graduation

Berkeley, CA USA